English Edition

Sun, Nov 24, 2024

* More
    
    * News18 Initiatives
    * Network18 Group Sites
    * Know Us

Choose Language

English

* Top Trends
* News18 Initiatives
* Network18 Group Sites
* Know Us

Follow us on

In Trends:

* Follow Us

News18 Website and App Privacy Policy
=====================================

* For other Residents
* For EU, UK and California Residents

Network18 Media and Investments Limited, having its registered office at First Floor, Empire Complex, 414, Senapati Bapat Marg, Lower Parel, Mumbai - 400013, India (“we”, “us”, “our”, “Network18”, “News18”) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal data, your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to all products and/or services offered by us to all individuals (“you”, “your”, “user”).

This Policy explains how we collect, receive, store, disclose, share, and use your personal data for the purpose of your participation and consumption of our products and/or services offered by us through our website and/or software application (collectively, “Platform”) or during any interaction with us, and how you can exercise your privacy rights.

Before using our Platform or availing any of our products and/or services, you are advised to carefully read this Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Policy, please do not access this Platform. By visiting and/or using our Platform, you are consenting to process your personal data in the manner as set forth in this Policy.

1\. DATA PRIVACY DISCLAIMER
---------------------------

The scope of this policy is limited to the product and/or services provided by us within the territory of India and applies to users who request for these products and/or services within the Indian territory.

2\. WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?
-----------------------------------------------

When you interact with us, we collect different types of information from you based on the type of interaction.

_“Personal Data”_ means any data about an individual who is identifiable by or in relation to such data.

_“Processing”, “Processed”, “Process”_ in relation to personal data, means a wholly or partly automated operation or set of operations performed on digital personal data, and includes operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, retrieval, use, alignment, or combination, indexing, sharing, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, restriction, erasure, or destruction.

We endeavor to collect only such personal data that is reasonably necessary to perform our services for you. When you interact with our Platform or otherwise us, we may collect the following personal data from you directly:

1\. **General Data –** your first name, last name, email, mobile number, address with Pin Code as well as your preferred language;

2\. **Government Identification Data –** data that enables us to identify you, e.g. your Aadhaar card and PAN card;

3\. **Authentication –** data required for authentication, such as username and password;

4\. **Technical and Network Activity Data –** data about your device and your usage of our Platform, including your IP address, device ID, hardware model and version, mobile network information, operating system and other online identifiers, type of browser, browsing history, search history, access time, pages viewed, URLs clicked on, forms submitted, and physical location;

5\. **Financial Data –** your bank details, including account name, account number, cancelled cheque;

6\. **Employment Details-** your employment details, such as company name, designation, education qualification, and resume

You can choose not to give us personal data when we ask you for it. If you decide not to give us your personal data, it may restrict our relationship with you.

3\. HOW DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
-----------------------------------------

**Information you directly provide to us:**

You may choose to provide us with the data, which is essential for us to deliver the products and/or services you request. Without this data, we may not be able to provide you with all the requested products and/or services;

* Use our Platform;
* Share or use your social media profile to contact us;
* Enter a contest or competition organised by us;
* Engage with one of our sales representatives;
* Get in touch for support or to provide feedback/ queries;
* Attend an online as well as on ground event;
* Ask questions or seek clarification regarding our products or services;
* To view any news, quiz or polls related services offered by us through the Platform.

**Information you provide to us voluntarily:**

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Platform, we may collect and store such data.

We may collect additional data at other times, when you provide feedback(s), modify your content or email preferences, respond to surveys, or communicate with us. This data may include your name, e-mail id, mobile number, etc.

**Information we collect automatically:**

We collect data about you, your interactions with us, as well as data regarding your computer or other devices used to access our Platform. This source may include, but is not limited to:

* Activities on the Platform such as type of pages viewed, time spent on pages, search queries etc.;
* Your interactions with our email, customer care and contact us Platform;
* Geo-location data through IP addresses;
* Device information like device id, device model etc. and other unique identifiers;
* Data collected via the use of cookies.

**Information we collect from other sources:**

We may collect or receive data about you from third-party sources and process this data in accordance with this policy. The sources may include, but is not limited to:

* Publicly accessible sources;
* Marketing vendors;
* Event management agencies;
* Social media Platforms.

If you connect your social media account to our Platform, you will share certain personal data from your social media account with us. This may include your name, email address, photo, list of social media contacts, and any other data you make accessible to us.

4\. LAWFUL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA
--------------------------------------------------

We will collect personal data by lawful and fair means and, where appropriate, with the knowledge of the individual concerned. We only collect and process personal data about you where we have a lawful basis. Lawful basis on which we would process data from you includes:

* Obtaining explicit consent from you,
* Processing for legitimate uses where processing is necessary in order to provide you with our products and/or services, such as:

1. To enforce our terms and conditions;
2. To ensure compliance with our legal obligations and to also comply with our obligations towards public authorities;
3. To enforce any legal right or claim;
4. For responding to a medical emergency involving a threat to your health or life or that of any other individual;
5. For taking measures to ensure safety of, or provide assistance or services to any individual any disaster, or any breakdown of public order;
6. For legal and compliance reasons, such as the prevention, detection, or investigation of a crime, loss prevention or prevention of fraud;
7. As otherwise described to you at the time of collection of your personal data.

5\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
-------------------------------------

We use your personal data for the purposes we have described below in this privacy notice, or for purposes which are reasonably compatible to the ones described.

**To manage our relationship with you.**

We will use your personal data to:

* Verify your identity; to help provide our products and/or services and to administer those products and/or services;
* Communicate with you concerning our service (for example by email, push notifications text messaging, and online messaging channels), so that we communicate news regarding the Platform to you, details about new features and content available on our platform;
* For marketing (where you have agreed to this) and for market research purposes, including internal demographic studies, to provide, optimize and personalize our products and/or services and to send you newsletters and data (where you have agreed to this) about our products and/or services;
* Provide online or offline products and/or services such as contests and employment opportunities;
* Identify you and authenticate your access rights access to our Platform;
* Invite you to provide feedback, surveys or attend events;
* Personalize your experience when interacting with us;
* To respond to your queries and provide you with data when you request it or when we believe our products and/or services may be of interest to you. If we intend to share electronic marketing with you, we will ask for your consent where required and you can opt out at any time.

**To manage and improve our processes and our business operations.**

We will use your personal data to:

* Manage our network and information systems security;
* Manage our workforce effectively;
* Perform data analyses, auditing and research to help us deliver and improve our digital Platform, content and products and/or services;
* Monitor and analyse trends, usage and activities in connection with our products and/or services to understand which parts of our products and/or services are of the most interest and to improve them accordingly.

**To achieve other purposes.**

We shall also use your personal data for legal and regulatory purposes, such as:

* For our internal and external audit requirements and for information security purposes;
* To gain insights and feedback on our products and/or services in order to correct or improve them, by analysing data from external sources such as Google, Facebook and Twitter (and others).

6\. HOW DO WE USE PERSONAL DATA WHEN YOU VISIT OUR OFFICES?
-----------------------------------------------------------

When you visit our offices, we process your personal data in accordance with this privacy statement and some specific information regarding the use of visitor data and the potential use of CCTV in our offices is provided in the reception area.

7\. HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
-----------------------------------------

We implement reasonable technical and organizational measures in relation to the data and personal data that is processed by us. We take reasonable measures to protect all personal data from unauthorized processing or accidental disclosure, alteration, misuse, destruction or loss or unauthorized access and modification that compromises the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of such data.

While we endeavor to always protect our Platform, operations and data against unauthorized access, use, modification, and disclosure, due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that any data, during transmission or while stored on our systems, will be safe and secure from intrusion by others.

8\. YOUR RIGHTS IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR PERSONAL DATA
-----------------------------------------------------

We respect your right to access and control your personal data, and we will respond to requests to exercise your rights under applicable laws and, where applicable, will correct, update, or erase your personal data.

**You have the following rights:**

* **Right to access data :** At any point, you can contact us for a summary of your personal data we hold about you, the processing activities undertaken with respect to such personal data, the identities of all those persons with whom your personal data has been shared by us along with the description of the personal data so shared, and any other data related to your personal data and its processing.
* **Right to request correction:** If your personal data is incomplete, inaccurate, misleading, or out of date, you can inform us about the same and your personal data will be corrected, completed, or updated.
* **Right to request erasure:** If you believe that we should discontinue the use of your personal data, you have the option to request the deletion of your personal data, unless retention is necessary for compliance with any law for the time being in force.
* **Right of grievance redressal:** In case of any grievance, you can also raise a request to alter your consent choices at **[dpo@nw18.com](mailto:dpo@nw18.com)**.
* **Right to nominate:** In the event of death or incapacity to exercise these rights, you can nominate any other individual to exercise such rights.
* **Right to withdraw your consent:** You can withdraw your consent easily by emailing us on [dpo@nw18.com](mailto:dpo@nw18.com). The withdrawal of consent previously granted for the processing of personal data does not affect the lawfulness of the processing until the withdrawal. However, opting out will result in cessation of the respective services.

For exercising any of your rights, you can contact us using [dpo@nw18.com](mailto:dpo@nw18.com). We will need you to furnish proof of your identity before you can exercise these rights. We may not be able to process any requests made in the event you fail to establish your identity, or if we are unable to authenticate your identity.

9\. SHARING/DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA
---------------------------------------

As far as this is necessary for the purposes set out above, we will share your personal data with the following recipients who either have a need to know and who will process it for us based on our instructions and for no other purpose:

**General Disclosure:**

We may disclose your personal data will include:

* Our related companies;
* We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Platform;
* All our employees and contractors are required to follow our data protection and security policies when handling personal data;
* We’ll share or disclose your personal data outside of the Platform when we have your consent. For example, providing SMS and E-mail related services such as marketing newsletters, promotions and offers;
* Your personal data might also have to be shared in the event of a merger, sale, restructure, acquisition, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets, or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

**External service providers:**

Occasionally, to provide our products and/or services, it is necessary to collaborate with external service providers. We may use these service providers to assist us with some features or functions of our Platform. These external service providers shall process your personal data on our behalf subject to appropriate safeguards only insofar as it is necessary for them to provide their products and/or services to us. Our prior authorization is required before they are permitted to transfer responsibility for processing personal data to a third party.

**Business Transfers:**

We provide personal data to our affiliates and other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

In the event if we merge with or acquired by another company or in case of re-organization or re-structuring of business, we and our affiliates may share your personal data, wholly or in part, with another business entity.

**Courts and public authorities:**

We will share personal data when required for the following purposes:

* To comply with legal obligations and respond to requests from government agencies, including law enforcement agencies and other public authorities;
* To prevent or detect or investigate offences or cyber incidents or for the prosecution or punishment of offences;
* To raise or defend against legal claims;
* To protect our users, systems, and products and/or services.

We only share your personal data with recipients that have an adequate level of data protection by implementing appropriate technical and organizational security measures, or we take measures to ensure that all recipients provide an adequate level of data protection as prescribed by applicable law. We do not sell your personal data to anyone.

10\. PERSONAL DATA TRANSFER, STORAGE AND PROCESSING GLOBALLY
------------------------------------------------------------

We operate globally and may transfer your personal data to our affiliates or third parties in territories outside India for the purposes described in this Policy in accordance with applicable data protection laws, provided that no such restriction is notified by the Government/ appropriate authority.

11\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
--------------------------------------------

We will retain your personal data which we have collected for as long as we reasonably consider it necessary for achieving the above mentioned purposes and as is permissible under applicable law. This is determined on a case-to-case basis.

We will delete your personal data whenever you request us to do so. However, we may archive and/or retain your personal data for as long as there are statutory retention obligations or potential legal claims are not, yet time barred.

12\. SAFEGUARDING THE PRIVACY OF CHILDREN
-----------------------------------------

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal data from minors. Our products and/or services are not designed for any person who is under 18 years of age, and we do not knowingly permit such persons to register for products and/ or services or share data through any of the web forms without verifiable consent from minors’ parents or lawful guardians. Further, we do not undertake tracking or behavioral monitoring of children or targeted advertising directed at children.

If we learn that we have collected personal data from a minor without verified parental consent, we will erase such personal data.

If you believe that a child under 18 years may have provided us their personal data, please contact us on [dpo@nw18.com](mailto:dpo@nw18.com).

13\. CONTACT INFORMATION
------------------------

If you have questions or comments regarding this Policy or want to exercise any of your rights or express your grievances regarding the processing of your personal data, please contact us using the contact details given below:

Network18 Media and Investments Limited

**Data Protection Officer  
Apurv Narula  
**

If you are not satisfied with the resolution provided you may log your complaint with the Data Protection Board of India following the procedure prescribed by them.

14\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
-----------------------------------

We reserve the right to change this Policy at our sole discretion at any time. Any material changes to this Policy will be posted on this page. We encourage you to review this Policy regularly for such changes. The updated Privacy Policy will take effect as soon as it has been updated.

This Policy was last updated as of 14th November 2024.

Nov 24, 2024

---------------------------------------------------------

[LIVE TV
-------](https://www.news18.com/livetv/)

TRENDING VIDEOS
---------------

Latest Blogs
------------

[Photogallery
------------](https://www.news18.com/photogallery/)

Trending Topics

Hot On Social

Popular Categories

Language Sites

Network18 Group Sites

Follow Us On

News18 App

CNN name, logo and all associated elements ® and © 2024 Cable News Network LP, LLLP. A Time Warner Company. All rights reserved. CNN and the CNN logo are registered marks of Cable News Network, LP LLLP, displayed with permission. Use of the CNN name and/or logo on or as part of NEWS18.com does not derogate from the intellectual property rights of Cable News Network in respect of them. © Copyright Network18 Media and Investments Ltd 2024. All rights reserved.
